# Jake R. Hempel

504 Bloomfield Ave. Apt. 2A2 Caldwell, NJ 07006

973 632 5837 jakehempel@gmail.com

#### **SUMMARY**

Ever since I was very young, I always had a passion for technology and a strong fascination for learning more about them. Since I was 14 years old I've been teaching myself the nuances of computers and excited to take this knowledge into the workforce and pursue a career in the computer science and cyber security field.

## **Education**

# **Rutgers School of Arts and Sciences**

Cyber Security/Computer Science — September 2015 - May 2019

## Relevant Coursework:

- Information Technology and Informatics
- Technical Writing Essentials
- AP Computer Science
- Computer Aided Drafting

# Work Experience

# **Rutgers Digital Classroom Services — Support Specialist**

New Brunswick, NJ — April 2017 – Present

Worked primarily as part of a build team constructing classroom podiums with embedded computer systems for educational use. Duties included installing and wiring components within the podiums as well as storage room organization.

#### Air Force ROTC — Cadet

New Brunswick, NJ — August 2015 – November 2016 Partook in the military leadership program offered by the Air Force Reserve Officer Training Corps at Rutgers New Brunswick. Practiced professionalism, discipline, and embodied the core values of integrity, service, and excellence.

#### **Self** — Personal/Game Server Administrator

Caldwell, NJ — December 2012 – Present Administrates multiple personal network Linux-based server computers for both personal and commercial usage. Made sure servers were running efficiently and were well maintained.

## **Great Notch Inn** — Barback/Assistant Bartender

Little Falls, NJ — May 2014 - Present

Helped assure bar was properly supplied, cleaned the building, helped solve customer disputes, and assured patrons had a pleasant experience.

## **SKILLS**

- Microsoft Office Suite, including Excel, Powerpoint, and Word
- Server computer administration
- Knowledge of Linux and Unix-Like operating systems
- Great communication skills

- Advanced problem-solving and troubleshooting skills
- Programing Languages: C++, Java, Python, HTML, CSS, Javascript, PHP
- Photoshop